Disney makes the classical musical more magical than ever!
Annie is a music, family, comedy film directed by Rob Marshall.
Things seem pretty bad for a young girl living a
"hard-knock life" in an orphanage.
Fed up with the dastardly Miss Hannigan, Annie escapes the
run-down orphanage determined to find her mom and dad.
It's an adventure that takes her from the cold, mean streets of New York to the warm, comforting arms of
bighearted billionaire Oliver Warbucks - with plenty of mischief and music in between.
Annie, played by Alicia Morton.
Miss Agatha Hannigan, played by Kathy Bates.
Oliver Warbucks, played by Victor Garber.
Daniel Francis "Rooster" Hannigan, played by Alan Cumming.
Miss Grace Farrell, played by Audra McDonald.
Lily St. Regis, played by Kristin Chenoweth.
Annie is a 1999 American musical comedy drama television film from The Wonderful World of Disney, adapted from the 1977 Broadway musical of the same name
by Charles Strouse, Martin Charnin, and Thomas Meehan, which in turn is based on the 1924 Little Orphan Annie comic strip by Harold Gray.
It is the first remake and the second film adaptation of the musical following the 1982
theatrical film starring Aileen Quinn, Carol Burnett, and Albert Finney.
It was directed by Rob Marshall, written by Irene Mecchi, and produced by Chris Montan Productions,
Storyline Entertainment, Columbia TriStar Television, and Walt Disney Television.
It stars Kathy Bates, Alan Cumming, Audra McDonald, Kristin Chenoweth, Victor Garber, Andrea McArdle, and introducing Alicia Morton in her film debut
as the titular character with supporting roles by Lalaine, Danielle Wilson, Sarah Hyland, Erin Adams, Nanea Miyata, and Marissa Rago.
Annie premiered on ABC on November 7, 1999.
The program proved to be popular during its initial airing, with an estimated 26.3 million viewers,
making it the second-most-watched Disney film ever to air on ABC behind Cinderella (1997).
This version earned two Emmy Awards and a George Foster Peabody Award.
It would be followed by a third film adaptation of the musical in 2014 and a
fourth adaptation that was a live NBC production of the musical.
The film explores themes of child abuse, holiday, musical, based
on play or musical, franklin delano roosevelt.
The tone is lighthearted.